<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vmug on VirtualMachinery</title>
    <link>/tags/vmug/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Vmug on VirtualMachinery</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2016 09:30:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/vmug/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>UK VMUG UserCon - Community Focus - #vDM30in30</title>
      <link>/2016/11/10/uk-vmug-usercon-community-focus-vdm30in30/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2016 09:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/11/10/uk-vmug-usercon-community-focus-vdm30in30/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;re now a mere week away from the VMUG UK UserCon on 17th November, but there is still time toregister ahead the day itself. You should also remember that you can simply turn up on the day, as always. We&amp;rsquo;ll be happy to see you either way. If you want to come to the vCurry the night before (7PM - 9PM, in the Premier Suite at the Motorcycle Museum) then it&amp;rsquo;s best to pre-register for that so we know how many people want feeding.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UK VMUG UserCon, November 17th! #vDM30in30</title>
      <link>/2016/11/03/uk-vmug-usercon-november-17th-vdm30in30/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2016 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/11/03/uk-vmug-usercon-november-17th-vdm30in30/</guid>
      <description>In just a couple of weeks, I&amp;rsquo;ll be attending my fourth UK VMUG UserCon, which is set to be the biggest VMUG event in the UK this year. As usual, the UserCon is being held at the National Motorcycle Museum, close to the NEC and Birmingham Airport. This years date for the diary is Thursday 17th November. With the demise of the physical vForum event, this should be the biggest VMware related gathering in the UK this year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMworld Europe 2016 Thursday</title>
      <link>/2016/10/27/vmworld-europe-2016-thursday-1-week-on/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2016 23:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/10/27/vmworld-europe-2016-thursday-1-week-on/</guid>
      <description>The last day of the show is always the quietest day. Some people are travelling home early, there&amp;rsquo;s less sessions around, certainly no parties after hours to plan for, the solutions exchange gets torn down and basically, everyone&amp;rsquo;s knackered.
My Thursday was relatively gentle, as a reflection of all of the above. I did have a few sessions booked, but in the end, I ducked most of them, other than the mandatory TAM session, as everything is available online afterwards and there were still some vendors to see, some conversations to have, some people to catch up with, generally some time to be sociable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMware Europe 2016 Wednesday</title>
      <link>/2016/10/26/vmware-europe-2016-wednesday-1-week-on/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2016 23:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/10/26/vmware-europe-2016-wednesday-1-week-on/</guid>
      <description>AKA TAM day 2 for me, I’d got so many TAM sessions planned that it was going to prove difficult to keep the step average up!
TAM 3842 – VMware Cloud on AWS Wednesday morning saw me wake up to discover a session which I did not have on my calendar when I planned my sessions, although I was rather pleased to see it there, given that it was about #VMConAWS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMware Europe 2016 Tuesday</title>
      <link>/2016/10/25/vmware-europe-2016-tuesday-1-week-on/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2016 23:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/10/25/vmware-europe-2016-tuesday-1-week-on/</guid>
      <description>This post will focus on the better part of the VMworld Tuesday, from both a time and an enjoyment perspective. Things didn&amp;rsquo;t start too well, I&amp;rsquo;d not gone to bed too late, but it seemed that I was party to Barcelona&amp;rsquo;s loudest ever relationship breakup which took place outside my window at about 4.30 AM, which meant that I failed to get to the vBreakfast for 7AM (sorry Fred, I definitely will make it one year!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMworld Europe 2016 TAM Day</title>
      <link>/2016/10/24/vmworld-europe-2016-tam-day-1-week-on/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2016 08:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/10/24/vmworld-europe-2016-tam-day-1-week-on/</guid>
      <description>Kicking off the conference in the best way possible is attendance at TAM day (or Partner day if that&amp;rsquo;s your thing). TAM day is a relatively structured day with a number of sessions and of course, that access to the other parts of VMworld which are open on the Monday. There&amp;rsquo;s a growing number of people arriving on the Monday who are neither TAM nor PEX attendees, but there&amp;rsquo;s other conference activities to keep them going too.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMworld Europe 2016 Sunday</title>
      <link>/2016/10/23/vmworld-europe-2016-sunday-1-week-on/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2016 23:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/10/23/vmworld-europe-2016-sunday-1-week-on/</guid>
      <description>Not sure if this was day 0, day -1 or what, but this is where it all begins for a serious percentage of the VMworld attendees that I know. The normal approach for most people who are going to TAM or PEX things on Monday is to get in on Sunday and then head to the vRockstar party.
This year I&amp;rsquo;d got an early flight out of Gatwick so was in BCN before the shuttle buses started running, but there&amp;rsquo;s lots of ways to get from the Airport to both the conference site (particularly via the new-for-this-year Fira metro station, which is on L9 Sud along with the airport terminals) and also in to town itself, usually by bus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New blood in the London VMUG Committee</title>
      <link>/2015/12/12/new-blood-in-the-london-vmug-committee/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2015 23:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/12/12/new-blood-in-the-london-vmug-committee/</guid>
      <description>I attended my third UK VMUG Conference on the 19th of November (again at the National Motorcycle Museum) an event which is put on by the London VMUG Committee. As planned, I spent the majority of the day in the Community Track, lending my support to all the folks from this amazing community who&amp;rsquo;d come from near and far to present sessions. What with the vCurry and the vQuiz the night before, which gives folks a chance to catch up with old friends and meet new ones, the UK&amp;rsquo;s National VMUG conference is always a great event.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMworld Europe 2015 Wednesday everything else</title>
      <link>/2015/10/18/vmworld-wednesday-everything-else/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2015 14:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/10/18/vmworld-wednesday-everything-else/</guid>
      <description>Rubrik The first thing I had on my agenda after the General Session was to take a look at Rubrik, one of the companies that have been getting a fair aount of buzz lately and so I took the opportunity to go and find out why. A hyperconverged type solution, a number of blocks (briks, obviously) a nice interface, dedupe, replication, all that seems to be the thing to do these days.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Speaking at January&#39;s LonVMUG</title>
      <link>/post/2015-02-19-about-speaking-at-januarys-lonvmug/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2015 13:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2015-02-19-about-speaking-at-januarys-lonvmug/</guid>
      <description>Ask people what their fears are and with the overwhelming majority, you&amp;rsquo;ll get to public speaking sooner rather than later. Most people would rather do almost anything else, so to go and present to a room full of technical experts and be judged by them all, when you could just sit back and listen to someone else, in blissful anonymity? Well, surely there&amp;rsquo;s no decision to be made? As a consequence, it&amp;rsquo;s no surprise that the erstwhile LonVMUG ctte.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EVALExperience</title>
      <link>/2015/02/08/evalexperience/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2015 03:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/02/08/evalexperience/</guid>
      <description>In a move that I have to say that I did not see coming (but then I think no-one did) VMUG recently announced that subscribers to their VMUG Advantage initiative would also receive EVALExperience licenses for a number of vSphere related products meaning that these products are now available for use with a 365 day license which you can renew as long as you maintain your VMUG Advantage subscription .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LonVMUG January 22nd 2015 - vFactor, vBeers and more</title>
      <link>/2015/01/17/lonvmug-january-22nd-2015-vfactor-vbeers-and-more/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2015 19:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/01/17/lonvmug-january-22nd-2015-vfactor-vbeers-and-more/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s nearly time for the first #LonVMUG of 2015. As usual, a cracking line-up has been finalised for this all-day event, but for myself and 4 other delegates, this will be an extra special day, cos we get to present!
Long-time LonVMUG stalwart Mike Laverick put together a #Feed4ward initiative in cahoots with
Duncan Epping and Scott Lowe as an attempt to solicit more community content at VMUGs around the world by mentoring would be presenters before their big day in front of an audience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LonVMUG, vBeers and a vCurry!</title>
      <link>/2013/07/05/lonvmug-vbeers-and-a-vcurry/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2013 19:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/07/05/lonvmug-vbeers-and-a-vcurry/</guid>
      <description>Wow! I nearly didn&amp;rsquo;t make it. A particularly &amp;ldquo;late one at the office&amp;rdquo; the night before saw me get to bed just short of 4am, with the prospect of a couple of hours train journey for a 9 something LonVMUG start. So, forget all about starting the day at 6am then.
The late start to the day turned out to be particularly gutting as the Twitter chat around the event pretty much ceased whilst Frank Dennerman was doing his presentation, so I was pretty miffed that I didn&amp;rsquo;t catch it live as it was obviously getting everyone&amp;rsquo;s attention.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>