<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Community on VirtualMachinery</title>
    <link>/tags/community/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Community on VirtualMachinery</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2016 09:30:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/community/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>UK VMUG UserCon - Community Focus - #vDM30in30</title>
      <link>/2016/11/10/uk-vmug-usercon-community-focus-vdm30in30/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2016 09:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/11/10/uk-vmug-usercon-community-focus-vdm30in30/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;re now a mere week away from the VMUG UK UserCon on 17th November, but there is still time toregister ahead the day itself. You should also remember that you can simply turn up on the day, as always. We&amp;rsquo;ll be happy to see you either way. If you want to come to the vCurry the night before (7PM - 9PM, in the Premier Suite at the Motorcycle Museum) then it&amp;rsquo;s best to pre-register for that so we know how many people want feeding.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fun with CloudCred! #vDM30in30</title>
      <link>/2016/11/09/fun-with-cloudcred-vdm30in30/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2016 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/11/09/fun-with-cloudcred-vdm30in30/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s a triple point Tuesday (well, it was when I wrote this and it&amp;rsquo;s OK, they are all triple point Tuesdays) so what better day to take a look at CloudCred and see what it&amp;rsquo;s all about? This is another post as part of the vDM30in30 series that I am trying to keep up with.
CloudCred was launched by VMware early in 2013 as a learning site, with a pretty solid gamification angle to it, which is what a lot of people were doing at the time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UK VMUG UserCon, November 17th! #vDM30in30</title>
      <link>/2016/11/03/uk-vmug-usercon-november-17th-vdm30in30/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2016 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/11/03/uk-vmug-usercon-november-17th-vdm30in30/</guid>
      <description>In just a couple of weeks, I&amp;rsquo;ll be attending my fourth UK VMUG UserCon, which is set to be the biggest VMUG event in the UK this year. As usual, the UserCon is being held at the National Motorcycle Museum, close to the NEC and Birmingham Airport. This years date for the diary is Thursday 17th November. With the demise of the physical vForum event, this should be the biggest VMware related gathering in the UK this year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMworld Europe 2016 Thursday</title>
      <link>/2016/10/27/vmworld-europe-2016-thursday-1-week-on/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2016 23:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/10/27/vmworld-europe-2016-thursday-1-week-on/</guid>
      <description>The last day of the show is always the quietest day. Some people are travelling home early, there&amp;rsquo;s less sessions around, certainly no parties after hours to plan for, the solutions exchange gets torn down and basically, everyone&amp;rsquo;s knackered.
My Thursday was relatively gentle, as a reflection of all of the above. I did have a few sessions booked, but in the end, I ducked most of them, other than the mandatory TAM session, as everything is available online afterwards and there were still some vendors to see, some conversations to have, some people to catch up with, generally some time to be sociable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMware Europe 2016 Wednesday</title>
      <link>/2016/10/26/vmware-europe-2016-wednesday-1-week-on/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2016 23:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/10/26/vmware-europe-2016-wednesday-1-week-on/</guid>
      <description>AKA TAM day 2 for me, I’d got so many TAM sessions planned that it was going to prove difficult to keep the step average up!
TAM 3842 – VMware Cloud on AWS Wednesday morning saw me wake up to discover a session which I did not have on my calendar when I planned my sessions, although I was rather pleased to see it there, given that it was about #VMConAWS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMware Europe 2016 Tuesday</title>
      <link>/2016/10/25/vmware-europe-2016-tuesday-1-week-on/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2016 23:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/10/25/vmware-europe-2016-tuesday-1-week-on/</guid>
      <description>This post will focus on the better part of the VMworld Tuesday, from both a time and an enjoyment perspective. Things didn&amp;rsquo;t start too well, I&amp;rsquo;d not gone to bed too late, but it seemed that I was party to Barcelona&amp;rsquo;s loudest ever relationship breakup which took place outside my window at about 4.30 AM, which meant that I failed to get to the vBreakfast for 7AM (sorry Fred, I definitely will make it one year!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMworld Europe 2016 Sunday</title>
      <link>/2016/10/23/vmworld-europe-2016-sunday-1-week-on/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2016 23:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/10/23/vmworld-europe-2016-sunday-1-week-on/</guid>
      <description>Not sure if this was day 0, day -1 or what, but this is where it all begins for a serious percentage of the VMworld attendees that I know. The normal approach for most people who are going to TAM or PEX things on Monday is to get in on Sunday and then head to the vRockstar party.
This year I&amp;rsquo;d got an early flight out of Gatwick so was in BCN before the shuttle buses started running, but there&amp;rsquo;s lots of ways to get from the Airport to both the conference site (particularly via the new-for-this-year Fira metro station, which is on L9 Sud along with the airport terminals) and also in to town itself, usually by bus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New site launch - OpenHomelab</title>
      <link>/2016/05/10/new-site-launch-openhomelab/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2016 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/05/10/new-site-launch-openhomelab/</guid>
      <description>If you have a Homelab or if you are thinking of constructing a Homelab, if you need to plan on a budget or want to know what everyone else is using, if you&amp;rsquo;ve wondered if you&amp;rsquo;re better off with a Cloudlab, but are not sure of the TCO involved, if you are studying for certifications, have a thirst for knowledge or just money to burn, then today sees the launch of a site designed just for you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New blood in the London VMUG Committee</title>
      <link>/2015/12/12/new-blood-in-the-london-vmug-committee/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2015 23:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/12/12/new-blood-in-the-london-vmug-committee/</guid>
      <description>I attended my third UK VMUG Conference on the 19th of November (again at the National Motorcycle Museum) an event which is put on by the London VMUG Committee. As planned, I spent the majority of the day in the Community Track, lending my support to all the folks from this amazing community who&amp;rsquo;d come from near and far to present sessions. What with the vCurry and the vQuiz the night before, which gives folks a chance to catch up with old friends and meet new ones, the UK&amp;rsquo;s National VMUG conference is always a great event.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMworld Europe 2015 Wednesday everything else</title>
      <link>/2015/10/18/vmworld-wednesday-everything-else/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2015 14:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/10/18/vmworld-wednesday-everything-else/</guid>
      <description>Rubrik The first thing I had on my agenda after the General Session was to take a look at Rubrik, one of the companies that have been getting a fair aount of buzz lately and so I took the opportunity to go and find out why. A hyperconverged type solution, a number of blocks (briks, obviously) a nice interface, dedupe, replication, all that seems to be the thing to do these days.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMworld Europe 2015 Wednesday General Session</title>
      <link>/2015/10/18/vmworld-wednesday-general-session/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2015 13:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/10/18/vmworld-wednesday-general-session/</guid>
      <description>Setup Poised with the same team as yesterday in the Hang Space awaiting the General Session, plus a couple of extra faces. The raised desks and UK plug adapters are well set up for the blogger types.

Cloud Stuff The cloud academy video from US VMworld opens up proceedings again, so I am expecting Carl, but it&amp;rsquo;s Sanjay Poonen, without people dressed as clouds or apps. He even slips in a Louis Suarez comment, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t bite.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMworld Europe 2015 Tuesday - Everything else (or TAM day 2)</title>
      <link>/2015/10/18/vmworld-tuesday-everything-else-or-tam-day-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2015 13:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/10/18/vmworld-tuesday-everything-else-or-tam-day-2/</guid>
      <description>TAM Session - ESXi Lifecycle I was straight off to the first of my TAM sessions after the general session, covering the ESXi lifecycle. The basic gist of this one is that VMware recognise that customers find it time consuming to maintain hosts and possibly difficult to spin up hosts. There&amp;rsquo;s one tool to provision (auto deploy), another place to go for initial configuration (host profiles) and then another to manage going forward (VUM).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMworld Europe 2015 Tuesday General Session</title>
      <link>/2015/10/13/vmworld-tuesday-general-session/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2015 11:48:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/10/13/vmworld-tuesday-general-session/</guid>
      <description>Setup A better start than last year since we were able to set up in the Hang Space before anyone started speaking. I managed to get a seat along with @julian_wood, @scott_lowe and @vcdxnz001 and had a go at the minimal setup, iPad for blogging, iPhone for twitter and a bluetooth keyboard. That wasn&amp;rsquo;t as &amp;ldquo;corridor warrior&amp;rdquo; as I had hoped, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t really cut it as a practical solution, is&amp;rsquo;s simply too slow to keep up and I struggled to blog and watch the twitter feed at the same time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMworld Europe 2015 Monday - TAM Day</title>
      <link>/2015/10/12/vmworld-monday-tam-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2015 23:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/10/12/vmworld-monday-tam-day/</guid>
      <description>Dell EMC Yeah, I know, Dell buys EMC for a proper Doctor Evil amount of money, on top of the billions it already owed the banks and VC guys who helped it to go private last year, but like I say, a debt is just a bunch of numbers on a piece of paper until someone actually calls it in. So whatever. VMware is still independent, just as it was last week, so we all have to wait to see just how this shakes out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMworld Europe 2015 Sunday</title>
      <link>/2015/10/11/vmworld-euope-sunday/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2015 22:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/10/11/vmworld-euope-sunday/</guid>
      <description>Ok, so first things first, I don&amp;rsquo;t know what day this is, day 1, day 0 or day -1, so it will have to stay as Sunday. That means flying to VMworld Europe day, a number of hours spent in transit, by now the normal Airbnb approach to staying in Barcelona, considering that basically all I will do in this apartment is sleep and shower. OK, and blog.
It&amp;rsquo;s only a couple of hours from Gatwick to Barcelona, but today&amp;rsquo;s transport involved car, train, plane, taxi, taxi, feet, which would have been a lot worse had I not been able to sponge lifts off of unnamed people&amp;rsquo;s expenses :-) You have to love this community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Speaking at January&#39;s LonVMUG</title>
      <link>/post/2015-02-19-about-speaking-at-januarys-lonvmug/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2015 13:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2015-02-19-about-speaking-at-januarys-lonvmug/</guid>
      <description>Ask people what their fears are and with the overwhelming majority, you&amp;rsquo;ll get to public speaking sooner rather than later. Most people would rather do almost anything else, so to go and present to a room full of technical experts and be judged by them all, when you could just sit back and listen to someone else, in blissful anonymity? Well, surely there&amp;rsquo;s no decision to be made? As a consequence, it&amp;rsquo;s no surprise that the erstwhile LonVMUG ctte.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EVALExperience</title>
      <link>/2015/02/08/evalexperience/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2015 03:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/02/08/evalexperience/</guid>
      <description>In a move that I have to say that I did not see coming (but then I think no-one did) VMUG recently announced that subscribers to their VMUG Advantage initiative would also receive EVALExperience licenses for a number of vSphere related products meaning that these products are now available for use with a 365 day license which you can renew as long as you maintain your VMUG Advantage subscription .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vExpert 2015</title>
      <link>/2015/02/05/vexpert-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2015 22:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/02/05/vexpert-2015/</guid>
      <description>Well, well, well. I&amp;rsquo;m pleased to say that I have been awarded the title of VMware vExpert for 2015, my first time! You can see the full list here on the VMTN site. Congratulations to all the new and returning vExperts named this year.
It&amp;rsquo;s rather humbling to gain this recognition and it really is great to see so many of the #LonVMUG folks who&amp;rsquo;ve helped me along the way be named as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LonVMUG January 22nd 2015 - vFactor, vBeers and more</title>
      <link>/2015/01/17/lonvmug-january-22nd-2015-vfactor-vbeers-and-more/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2015 19:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/01/17/lonvmug-january-22nd-2015-vfactor-vbeers-and-more/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s nearly time for the first #LonVMUG of 2015. As usual, a cracking line-up has been finalised for this all-day event, but for myself and 4 other delegates, this will be an extra special day, cos we get to present!
Long-time LonVMUG stalwart Mike Laverick put together a #Feed4ward initiative in cahoots with
Duncan Epping and Scott Lowe as an attempt to solicit more community content at VMUGs around the world by mentoring would be presenters before their big day in front of an audience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMWorld Europe 2014 - Day 3</title>
      <link>/2014/10/20/vmworld-europe-day-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2014 21:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2014/10/20/vmworld-europe-day-3/</guid>
      <description>The final day, an early start to the sessions with no keynote to overrun into the first session, so I went straight into a 9am breakout session.
Session: INF2311 - vCenter Server Architecture &amp;amp; Deployment Deep Dive Some good tips here for the folks running (or planning to run) vCenter 5.5 specifically around the placement of vCenter components. Do not, do not, do NOT run your Inventory service on a different server to your vCenter server service!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMworld Europe 2014 - Day 2</title>
      <link>/2014/10/20/vmworld-europe-day-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2014 17:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2014/10/20/vmworld-europe-day-2/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m on a bit of a roll now! The &amp;lsquo;second&amp;rsquo; day of VMworld Europe started with another keynote, just the same as San Fran (same general format, same general content). Fortunately for those of us wanting to blog/tweet during this, the doors that were closed yesterday were open by the time I got to the hangspace, so I was in and settled with a coffee and pain au chocolat before 9am.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMworld Europe 2014 - Day 1</title>
      <link>/2014/10/19/vmworld-europe-day-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2014 20:49:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2014/10/19/vmworld-europe-day-1/</guid>
      <description>Admittedly, I&amp;rsquo;d already been in Barcelona for a while after the TAM day (partner day for most people) on Monday, so we&amp;rsquo;d already had confusion amongst the bloggers as to what day it was., perhaps we should stick with &amp;lsquo;Tuesday&amp;rsquo; and have done with it? Apologies for any tense changes here, this post was mostly written at VMworld, but not published then.
Keynote This was my first opportunity to attend a European keynote, so I was hoping to be able to get ensconsed in the hangspace or the bloggers area and tweet or blog from there, whilst hoping it would be different from the US keynote.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMworld Europe 2014 - Prelude and TAM Day</title>
      <link>/2014/10/19/vmworld-europe-prelude-and-tam-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2014 20:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2014/10/19/vmworld-europe-prelude-and-tam-day/</guid>
      <description>I have to admit to being pretty excited to attend my first VMworld in 6 Years, this time with the additional perk of having the Monday lined up as well, as part of the TAM experience. Technical Account Manager, that is. Same day as Partner Day, but for those of us who warrant or buy this level of service, I guess. I work for a large American Company so this was something I get that I was not going to get so often, as my TAM is in the US, whereas I am not!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LonVMUG, vBeers and a vCurry!</title>
      <link>/2013/07/05/lonvmug-vbeers-and-a-vcurry/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2013 19:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/07/05/lonvmug-vbeers-and-a-vcurry/</guid>
      <description>Wow! I nearly didn&amp;rsquo;t make it. A particularly &amp;ldquo;late one at the office&amp;rdquo; the night before saw me get to bed just short of 4am, with the prospect of a couple of hours train journey for a 9 something LonVMUG start. So, forget all about starting the day at 6am then.
The late start to the day turned out to be particularly gutting as the Twitter chat around the event pretty much ceased whilst Frank Dennerman was doing his presentation, so I was pretty miffed that I didn&amp;rsquo;t catch it live as it was obviously getting everyone&amp;rsquo;s attention.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Now?</title>
      <link>/2013/05/24/why-now/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2013 17:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/05/24/why-now/</guid>
      <description>Why start a totally new blog about virtualisation topics at this late stage in the game, when there&amp;rsquo;s already a whole host of excellent sites out there? Sites I use myself regularly, too. I&amp;rsquo;ve shied away from this before, thinking that I will find it difficult to be on top of the game enough to provide useful content to complement existing sites.
Well, there&amp;rsquo;s this thing&amp;hellip; The other day I found out about a website calledCloudCred, which is basically a VMware backed educational website, which incentivises its members to develop knowledge and build collaborative teams via gamification.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>