<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vmworld on VirtualMachinery</title>
    <link>/categories/vmworld/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Vmworld on VirtualMachinery</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2016 23:30:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/vmworld/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>VMworld Europe 2016 Thursday</title>
      <link>/2016/10/27/vmworld-europe-2016-thursday-1-week-on/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2016 23:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/10/27/vmworld-europe-2016-thursday-1-week-on/</guid>
      <description>The last day of the show is always the quietest day. Some people are travelling home early, there&amp;rsquo;s less sessions around, certainly no parties after hours to plan for, the solutions exchange gets torn down and basically, everyone&amp;rsquo;s knackered.
My Thursday was relatively gentle, as a reflection of all of the above. I did have a few sessions booked, but in the end, I ducked most of them, other than the mandatory TAM session, as everything is available online afterwards and there were still some vendors to see, some conversations to have, some people to catch up with, generally some time to be sociable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMware Europe 2016 Wednesday</title>
      <link>/2016/10/26/vmware-europe-2016-wednesday-1-week-on/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2016 23:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/10/26/vmware-europe-2016-wednesday-1-week-on/</guid>
      <description>AKA TAM day 2 for me, I’d got so many TAM sessions planned that it was going to prove difficult to keep the step average up!
TAM 3842 – VMware Cloud on AWS Wednesday morning saw me wake up to discover a session which I did not have on my calendar when I planned my sessions, although I was rather pleased to see it there, given that it was about #VMConAWS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMware Europe 2016 Tuesday</title>
      <link>/2016/10/25/vmware-europe-2016-tuesday-1-week-on/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2016 23:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/10/25/vmware-europe-2016-tuesday-1-week-on/</guid>
      <description>This post will focus on the better part of the VMworld Tuesday, from both a time and an enjoyment perspective. Things didn&amp;rsquo;t start too well, I&amp;rsquo;d not gone to bed too late, but it seemed that I was party to Barcelona&amp;rsquo;s loudest ever relationship breakup which took place outside my window at about 4.30 AM, which meant that I failed to get to the vBreakfast for 7AM (sorry Fred, I definitely will make it one year!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMworld Europe 2016 General Session, eventually</title>
      <link>/2016/10/18/vmworld-europe-2016-general-session-eventually/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2016 08:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/10/18/vmworld-europe-2016-general-session-eventually/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to the General session today, it appears for once that there is more being announced in Europe than we got from Vegas. Given the early release of some training courses, the forthcoming general session is known to contain the release of vSphere 6.5 (and hence VSAN 6.5 also). The recent announcement of the #VMWonAWS setup, using vSphere Foundation, has also garnered massive interest (there&amp;rsquo;s not enough sessions on this and VMware are scrambling to put more on to satisfy the clamouring from the masses).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMworld Europe 2016 TAM Day</title>
      <link>/2016/10/24/vmworld-europe-2016-tam-day-1-week-on/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2016 08:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/10/24/vmworld-europe-2016-tam-day-1-week-on/</guid>
      <description>Kicking off the conference in the best way possible is attendance at TAM day (or Partner day if that&amp;rsquo;s your thing). TAM day is a relatively structured day with a number of sessions and of course, that access to the other parts of VMworld which are open on the Monday. There&amp;rsquo;s a growing number of people arriving on the Monday who are neither TAM nor PEX attendees, but there&amp;rsquo;s other conference activities to keep them going too.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMworld Europe 2016 Sunday</title>
      <link>/2016/10/23/vmworld-europe-2016-sunday-1-week-on/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2016 23:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/10/23/vmworld-europe-2016-sunday-1-week-on/</guid>
      <description>Not sure if this was day 0, day -1 or what, but this is where it all begins for a serious percentage of the VMworld attendees that I know. The normal approach for most people who are going to TAM or PEX things on Monday is to get in on Sunday and then head to the vRockstar party.
This year I&amp;rsquo;d got an early flight out of Gatwick so was in BCN before the shuttle buses started running, but there&amp;rsquo;s lots of ways to get from the Airport to both the conference site (particularly via the new-for-this-year Fira metro station, which is on L9 Sud along with the airport terminals) and also in to town itself, usually by bus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMworld Europe 2015 Thursday, or, TAM Day 3</title>
      <link>/2015/10/19/vmworld-thursday-or-tam-day-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2015 17:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/10/19/vmworld-thursday-or-tam-day-3/</guid>
      <description>A lot of folks head back home on Thursday, so the train and bus were both pretty empty this morning. The hardy folks who do make it in generally make use of the bag drop today for all those suitcases full of accumulated swag.
I had 5 sessions planned for Thursday, so for me, this was a busy day session wise. Most of these were TAM sessions, so TCC was my first port of call for some welcome tea and croissants.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMworld Europe 2015 Wednesday everything else</title>
      <link>/2015/10/18/vmworld-wednesday-everything-else/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2015 14:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/10/18/vmworld-wednesday-everything-else/</guid>
      <description>Rubrik The first thing I had on my agenda after the General Session was to take a look at Rubrik, one of the companies that have been getting a fair aount of buzz lately and so I took the opportunity to go and find out why. A hyperconverged type solution, a number of blocks (briks, obviously) a nice interface, dedupe, replication, all that seems to be the thing to do these days.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMworld Europe 2015 Wednesday General Session</title>
      <link>/2015/10/18/vmworld-wednesday-general-session/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2015 13:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/10/18/vmworld-wednesday-general-session/</guid>
      <description>Setup Poised with the same team as yesterday in the Hang Space awaiting the General Session, plus a couple of extra faces. The raised desks and UK plug adapters are well set up for the blogger types.

Cloud Stuff The cloud academy video from US VMworld opens up proceedings again, so I am expecting Carl, but it&amp;rsquo;s Sanjay Poonen, without people dressed as clouds or apps. He even slips in a Louis Suarez comment, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t bite.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMworld Europe 2015 Tuesday - Everything else (or TAM day 2)</title>
      <link>/2015/10/18/vmworld-tuesday-everything-else-or-tam-day-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2015 13:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/10/18/vmworld-tuesday-everything-else-or-tam-day-2/</guid>
      <description>TAM Session - ESXi Lifecycle I was straight off to the first of my TAM sessions after the general session, covering the ESXi lifecycle. The basic gist of this one is that VMware recognise that customers find it time consuming to maintain hosts and possibly difficult to spin up hosts. There&amp;rsquo;s one tool to provision (auto deploy), another place to go for initial configuration (host profiles) and then another to manage going forward (VUM).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMworld Europe 2015 Tuesday General Session</title>
      <link>/2015/10/13/vmworld-tuesday-general-session/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2015 11:48:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/10/13/vmworld-tuesday-general-session/</guid>
      <description>Setup A better start than last year since we were able to set up in the Hang Space before anyone started speaking. I managed to get a seat along with @julian_wood, @scott_lowe and @vcdxnz001 and had a go at the minimal setup, iPad for blogging, iPhone for twitter and a bluetooth keyboard. That wasn&amp;rsquo;t as &amp;ldquo;corridor warrior&amp;rdquo; as I had hoped, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t really cut it as a practical solution, is&amp;rsquo;s simply too slow to keep up and I struggled to blog and watch the twitter feed at the same time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMworld Europe 2015 Monday - TAM Day</title>
      <link>/2015/10/12/vmworld-monday-tam-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2015 23:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/10/12/vmworld-monday-tam-day/</guid>
      <description>Dell EMC Yeah, I know, Dell buys EMC for a proper Doctor Evil amount of money, on top of the billions it already owed the banks and VC guys who helped it to go private last year, but like I say, a debt is just a bunch of numbers on a piece of paper until someone actually calls it in. So whatever. VMware is still independent, just as it was last week, so we all have to wait to see just how this shakes out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMworld Europe 2015 Sunday</title>
      <link>/2015/10/11/vmworld-euope-sunday/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2015 22:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/10/11/vmworld-euope-sunday/</guid>
      <description>Ok, so first things first, I don&amp;rsquo;t know what day this is, day 1, day 0 or day -1, so it will have to stay as Sunday. That means flying to VMworld Europe day, a number of hours spent in transit, by now the normal Airbnb approach to staying in Barcelona, considering that basically all I will do in this apartment is sleep and shower. OK, and blog.
It&amp;rsquo;s only a couple of hours from Gatwick to Barcelona, but today&amp;rsquo;s transport involved car, train, plane, taxi, taxi, feet, which would have been a lot worse had I not been able to sponge lifts off of unnamed people&amp;rsquo;s expenses :-) You have to love this community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VSAN 6.1 and 6.NEXT</title>
      <link>/2015/09/01/vsan-6-1-and-6-next/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 13:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/09/01/vsan-6-1-and-6-next/</guid>
      <description>Cormac Hogan has posted a couple of blog posts in the last 24 hours detailing the new features offered by the newly announced (today?) release of VSAN 6.1 and also lifted the veil somewhat on what can be expected in the next release, including another VSAN beta signup offer.
Whatever you may think about the adoption rates for VSAN there&amp;rsquo;s no arguing with the pace of development coming out of VMware for this technology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMworld US 2015 Keynote thoughts</title>
      <link>/2015/08/31/vmworld-2015-keynote-thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2015 19:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/08/31/vmworld-2015-keynote-thoughts/</guid>
      <description>So here we go, The Keynote from the first day of VMworld 2015, San Fran. This is more a stream of thought than anything totally structured/sensible and is partly my notes to see what I need to go look at later on!
Apps and Cloud huh? Opening with a video before Carl Eschenbach takes the stage. There are a record 23,000 folks attending in person this year, somewhat different from the 1,200 in the first year, plus loads of folks like me watching from further afield.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMware Validated Designs announced</title>
      <link>/2015/08/31/vmware-validated-designs-announced/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2015 16:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/08/31/vmware-validated-designs-announced/</guid>
      <description>Sometime yesterday, VMware announced the existence of VMware Validated Designs, which are a series of architecture designs validated by VMware experts. These appear to be a number of fluid designs (sorry to use a brave liquid word there but you&amp;rsquo;ll see what I mean) which will be updated regularly, meaning that the design principles espoused within will not be stuck at a single release version and more importantly will not be stuck at a single product.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMworld Europe Session picks</title>
      <link>/2015/08/18/vmworld-europe-session-picks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2015 20:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/08/18/vmworld-europe-session-picks/</guid>
      <description>So, the VMworld Europe schedule builder opened up today and some of the sessions are already full up. Scary. Almost every guided lab session was full up by lunchtime on day 1, I wonder if the same folks got in to all of them, quite likely!
This is the list I am thinking of at the moment. I am sure this will get turned on it&amp;rsquo;s head when more info comes out about TAM Customer Central, additional sessions get announced after the releases announced at VMworld US and I&amp;rsquo;ll need time to take a look at the solutions exchange and talk toa ll the clever folks around the place.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMworld Europe 2014 - TAM Sessions</title>
      <link>/2014/10/23/vmworld-europe-tam-sessions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2014 00:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2014/10/23/vmworld-europe-tam-sessions/</guid>
      <description>An extra post about my favourite part of VMworld from the organised conference perspective&amp;hellip;
I thought that the TAM sessions were by far the best sessions I attended. None of them were presented by the most well known vRockstars (they were out in the normal breakout sessions, doing their thing - and from the ones I saw, doing it very well) the TAM sessions were all by the engineers and product managers who you don&amp;rsquo;t know as well, which was great.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMWorld Europe 2014 - Day 3</title>
      <link>/2014/10/20/vmworld-europe-day-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2014 21:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2014/10/20/vmworld-europe-day-3/</guid>
      <description>The final day, an early start to the sessions with no keynote to overrun into the first session, so I went straight into a 9am breakout session.
Session: INF2311 - vCenter Server Architecture &amp;amp; Deployment Deep Dive Some good tips here for the folks running (or planning to run) vCenter 5.5 specifically around the placement of vCenter components. Do not, do not, do NOT run your Inventory service on a different server to your vCenter server service!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMworld Europe 2014 - Day 2</title>
      <link>/2014/10/20/vmworld-europe-day-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2014 17:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2014/10/20/vmworld-europe-day-2/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m on a bit of a roll now! The &amp;lsquo;second&amp;rsquo; day of VMworld Europe started with another keynote, just the same as San Fran (same general format, same general content). Fortunately for those of us wanting to blog/tweet during this, the doors that were closed yesterday were open by the time I got to the hangspace, so I was in and settled with a coffee and pain au chocolat before 9am.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMworld Europe 2014 - Day 1</title>
      <link>/2014/10/19/vmworld-europe-day-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2014 20:49:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2014/10/19/vmworld-europe-day-1/</guid>
      <description>Admittedly, I&amp;rsquo;d already been in Barcelona for a while after the TAM day (partner day for most people) on Monday, so we&amp;rsquo;d already had confusion amongst the bloggers as to what day it was., perhaps we should stick with &amp;lsquo;Tuesday&amp;rsquo; and have done with it? Apologies for any tense changes here, this post was mostly written at VMworld, but not published then.
Keynote This was my first opportunity to attend a European keynote, so I was hoping to be able to get ensconsed in the hangspace or the bloggers area and tweet or blog from there, whilst hoping it would be different from the US keynote.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMworld Europe 2014 - Prelude and TAM Day</title>
      <link>/2014/10/19/vmworld-europe-prelude-and-tam-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2014 20:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2014/10/19/vmworld-europe-prelude-and-tam-day/</guid>
      <description>I have to admit to being pretty excited to attend my first VMworld in 6 Years, this time with the additional perk of having the Monday lined up as well, as part of the TAM experience. Technical Account Manager, that is. Same day as Partner Day, but for those of us who warrant or buy this level of service, I guess. I work for a large American Company so this was something I get that I was not going to get so often, as my TAM is in the US, whereas I am not!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMware enters the Hyper-Converged space with VMware EVO.</title>
      <link>/2014/08/25/vmware-enters-the-hyper-converged-space-with-vmware-evo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2014 23:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2014/08/25/vmware-enters-the-hyper-converged-space-with-vmware-evo/</guid>
      <description>In a move that justifies (if that&amp;rsquo;s the right word) the developments made by Nutanix, Simplivity et al, VMware announced two releases of their Hyper-Converged Infrastructure Appliance (HCIA) products, which are called VMware EVO. This is the Project Marvin initiative which has been whispered about for a while since an internal VMware poster was seen up on a wall by someone who shouldn&amp;rsquo;t have seen it! The EVO part means Evolution and the product names RAIL and RACK are down to the amount of space they take up in the datacentre.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMworld 2014 Day 1</title>
      <link>/2014/08/25/vmworld-2014-day-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2014 22:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2014/08/25/vmworld-2014-day-1/</guid>
      <description>A personal snapshot of some of the big news from the show;
The keynote from day 1 mentioned IT bravely delivering brave products by making brave decisions, bravely. There were also some new product numbers announced, which is what people really want to hear, I guess. I&amp;rsquo;m sure Pat Gelsinger broke the vSphere 6.0 Beta NDA by mentioning that it contained VVols, but who&amp;rsquo;s gonna tell him? There was also an update to the cloud stack, with vCloud Suite 5.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>