<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vrockstar on VirtualMachinery</title>
    <link>/tags/vrockstar/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Vrockstar on VirtualMachinery</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2016 23:55:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/vrockstar/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>VMworld Europe 2016 Sunday</title>
      <link>/2016/10/23/vmworld-europe-2016-sunday-1-week-on/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2016 23:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/10/23/vmworld-europe-2016-sunday-1-week-on/</guid>
      <description>Not sure if this was day 0, day -1 or what, but this is where it all begins for a serious percentage of the VMworld attendees that I know. The normal approach for most people who are going to TAM or PEX things on Monday is to get in on Sunday and then head to the vRockstar party.
This year I&amp;rsquo;d got an early flight out of Gatwick so was in BCN before the shuttle buses started running, but there&amp;rsquo;s lots of ways to get from the Airport to both the conference site (particularly via the new-for-this-year Fira metro station, which is on L9 Sud along with the airport terminals) and also in to town itself, usually by bus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMworld Europe 2015 Sunday</title>
      <link>/2015/10/11/vmworld-euope-sunday/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2015 22:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/10/11/vmworld-euope-sunday/</guid>
      <description>Ok, so first things first, I don&amp;rsquo;t know what day this is, day 1, day 0 or day -1, so it will have to stay as Sunday. That means flying to VMworld Europe day, a number of hours spent in transit, by now the normal Airbnb approach to staying in Barcelona, considering that basically all I will do in this apartment is sleep and shower. OK, and blog.
It&amp;rsquo;s only a couple of hours from Gatwick to Barcelona, but today&amp;rsquo;s transport involved car, train, plane, taxi, taxi, feet, which would have been a lot worse had I not been able to sponge lifts off of unnamed people&amp;rsquo;s expenses :-) You have to love this community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMworld Europe 2014 - Prelude and TAM Day</title>
      <link>/2014/10/19/vmworld-europe-prelude-and-tam-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2014 20:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2014/10/19/vmworld-europe-prelude-and-tam-day/</guid>
      <description>I have to admit to being pretty excited to attend my first VMworld in 6 Years, this time with the additional perk of having the Monday lined up as well, as part of the TAM experience. Technical Account Manager, that is. Same day as Partner Day, but for those of us who warrant or buy this level of service, I guess. I work for a large American Company so this was something I get that I was not going to get so often, as my TAM is in the US, whereas I am not!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>